Silva, Murillo

Goiania - Brazil murillov.dev@gmail.com | +55 62 983-196-600 www.linkedin.com/in/murillo-vieira

SUMMARY

Having over than 6 years of experience in the field as a Frontend and Fullstack developer, I've worked on important projects in every phase of the software development lifecycle, from business requirements collection to project delivery. Throught the code, I always try to add value to the company being aware of the company's perspectives and goals.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Identified performance issues an cut down the screen render time by four times, also reducing overfetch
- Led a team of 4 other Frontend developers and increased the amount of tasks delivered by the team by up to 25% per Sprint
- Given talks to a large community. Also helped 5 other people from coding basics to midlevel

CAREER

Frontend Engineer at Revelo

Developer Squad Supply Specialist Jan 2022 – Present • 1 yrs, 9 mos

Revelo is a company based on the US and Brazil that allocates top notch developers to corporations that are willing to create their own webapp or mobile app using the best technologies available. Furthermore, developers are also responsible for understanding the corporation's goals and providing the best service, based on their core business with a high quality control of software.

Role:

In my position as a Developer at Revelo, I've been a contractor for a single project thus far. There I work for Nerdwallet, a company whose goal is to provide information that educates users in making financial decisions. My assignments are:

- Help building out a style guide and core set of React components and templates.
- Explore technologies such as React and Next JS to support server-side rendering for speed and SEO.
- Design and build admin interfaces so our business analysts can seamlessly update website content and easily get analytics reports to track performance.
- Build tests using tools like Jest and Cypress to ensure the components are reliable enough.
- Update third part packages to it's most modern and seccure versions.

Tech Stack:

Git, ReactJS, Typescript, NextJS, ES7, Redux, React Hooks, Context API, Atomic Design, Styled Components, Chakra UI, Ruby on Rails, GraphQL, Webpack, Vite, HTML5, SCSS, Babel.

Senior Frontend Developer at SevenApps LLC

Developer Squad Supply Specialist Dec 2020 – Jan 2022 • 1 yrs, 2 mos

Role:

As a Developer at SevenApps, I worked on three projects. The most significant company was FanHero. There I helped with their newest version for the webapp for clients, which has the need of handling millions of simultaneous connections, hence thinking about solutions for problems like requests, performance, security among other issues.

Projects: FanHero Portal, Webapp; Mindlab: MindZup - Gamificated application for students; BestBarbers: Barber Management Webapp

Tech Stack & Concepts:

Git, ReactJS, NextJS, React Native, ES7, Redux, React Hooks, Context API, Atomic Design, Styled Components, Chakra UI, Rest, GraphQL, Gulp, Webpack, Babel, Docker, Google Cloud.

Frontend Developer at Nectar CRM

Biggest CRM company in Brazilian's midwest Nov 2018 – Dec 2020 • 2 yrs, 2 mos

Nectar is a regional CRM company which provides solutions for companies to manage relationships with their customers, selling procedures, Business Intelligence and a lot more. Integrated with Google, RD Station and a huge set of tools and enterprises, it helps companies boosts their sales process and strategy.

Responsibilities:

- Refactor of the Webapp with the new UX/UI set
- Development of new functionalities to the main software
- Create personalized documentation to help new hired developers to understand the applications
- Helped developing the new Mobile Application using React Native
- Development of Nectar CRM's main web app and bug solving issues
- Improvements on company's Backoffice app

Tech Stack:

AngularJS, Karma, ReactJS, React Native, Redux, Vue 2, HTML5, ES7, CSS3, Sass, Rest, Gulp, JSP, Git, Java 8.

Frontend Developer at Actuar

Leading provider of academic software in Brazil Jul 2017 – Nov 2018 • 1 yr 5 mos

Actuar is a company which focus on proving technology to gyms and web payment. In 18 months I was able to:

- Lead a team of developers applying SCRUM and working on the development of an ERP focused on gyms management and crossfit boxes
- Estimate the effort for new demands and performed verification of the artifacts of software engineering such as requirements, design, implementation and testing
- Give maintenance on a training app. Made responsive blogs and webpages for the company, also performing SEO

Tech Stack:

Angular 2+, Ionic 2, Typescript, Jest, Angular JS, Wordpress, Scrum, HTML5, ES6, CSS3, Sass, SVG, Git.

Internship Software Developer at Meta

Feb 2017 - Jul 2017 • 6 mos

Tech Stack:

JAVA, MongoDB, JSP, HTML and CSS with Bootstrap.

EDUCATION

University Degree

2014 - 2018 Universidade Federal de Goias

Bachelor of Computer Information Systems

Having also studied Computer Science since 2009, which included Formal Languages and Automata Theory, Compilers, Operating Systems, Algorithms and its Complexity.

Certificates

React Native with NodeJS and Firebase (28h); MERN Stack, Frontend to Backend (12h); Agile management with SCRUM (10h); Complete Javascript 2018 - Fundamentals to Master (35h); Web Design for Web Developers: UI/UX for Websites and Mobile (8h);

INTERESTS

- Help people to solve problems with code and great usability
- Grow as a developer and bring life to great ideas
- Know as many countries and cultures as possible

You can check out more at my personal website:

https://murilloves.github.io/dev/